The British Empire branded them as outlaws. The oppressed called them heroes.
True History of the Kelly Gang is a crime, drama,
western film directed by Justin Kurzel.
Set against the badlands of Australia where the English rule with a bloody fist and the Irish endure, Ned Kelly discovers he comes from a line of
Irish rebels — an uncompromising army of cross dressing bandits immortalised for terrorising their oppressors back in Ireland.
Fuelled by the unfair arrest of his mother, Kelly recruits a wild bunch of warriors to plot one
of the most audacious attacks of anarchy and rebellion the country has ever seen.
Ned Kelly, played by George MacKay.
Sgt. Fitzpatrick, played by Nicholas Hoult.
Ellen Kelly, played by Essie Davis.
Harry Power, played by Russell Crowe.
Sergeant O'Neil, played by Charlie Hunnam.
Young Ned Kelly, played by Orlando Schwerdt.
True History of the Kelly Gang is a 2019 bushranger film directed by Justin Kurzel, written by
Shaun Grant, and based upon the 2000 novel of the same name by Peter Carey.
A fictionalised account of the life of bushranger and outlaw Ned Kelly, the film stars
George MacKay, Essie Davis, Nicholas Hoult, Charlie Hunnam, and Russell Crowe.
It had its world premiere at the Toronto International
Film Festival on 11 September 2019.
It was released in Australia on Australia Day 2020, by Transmission Films and Stan, in the United Kingdom on 28
February 2020, by Picturehouse Entertainment, and in the United States on 24 April 2020, by IFC Films.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
biography, 19th century, australian bush, bushranger.
The tone is emotional and intense.